May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records
May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records
- John H. Applebee, Minister, 1911-1929
  - [misc church repair], 1917-1921; Copy of letter dated June 4, 1917 to James Tracy re Calthrop estate and payments to his family. Copy of letter dated Nov 8, 1917 to James Tracy about raising money for Mrs. Calthrop's support and expenses for a church music. Bid submitted for George W. Reed for painting and repair of spire and roof, Apr. 4, 1919. Contract for repair of spire and roof. Copy of report of inspection of church building by Walter W. Edwards to Society President, Sept 27, 1920. Copy of letter requesting that repairs be made. Sept 27, 1920. Letter Sept 30, 1920 to FR Kimmey requesting estimates for repairs listed. Copy of letter recommending renovation and redecorating of church and organ, Dec. 27, 1920. Copy of letter requesting proposed installation of new furnace, Jan 31, 1921. Letter dated Mar 31, 1921 re changing church heat heating system to steam. May 31, 1921, copy of letter authorizing repairs. June 12, 1921 agreement authorizing repair and redecoration of interior of sanctuary. Sept 1921 letter of agreement regarding new woodwork behind pulpit. Artists drawing of proposed new woodwork. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - [new organ], 1911; Memorandum of agreement to build and install new organ by July 15, 1911. Specifications for the organ. Copy of letter, Apr. 27, 1911 re installation of organ. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - [misc], 1923; Letter to the congregation, July 1923 re Week of Mission, services by Dr. William M. Sullivan. (Note: JMH 1997, Was this Unitarian answer to Billy Sunday?) Invitation to seven evening meetings with William L. Sullivan DD. A copy of Layman's League introduction to Dr. Sullivan. Typed copy "A Forecast of Christianity" with suggestions for work after Dr. Sullivan's Mission by H. W. Jordan 1923. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Church directory. Xerox copy of seating chart for sanctuary. Envelope containing original of seating chart., 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - A card for 100th birthday of Harriet S. Mills (Mrs. C. de B. Mills). Photos of (1) Mrs. Goodrich, (2) Mrs. Mills, Bigelow and Goodrich., 1926 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - [misc], 1927; Typed copy of talk given at Calthrop dinner, Oct. 7, 1927: "A Radiant Personality: Dr. Samuel R. Calthrop." Essay or sermon in question and answer form, "The New consciousness of God." No date or author. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Memorial tributes on death of James Barnes, 2 copies. also Capt. Philip Lighthall and Charles W. Snow (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Playbill for Junior young people presentation of "The Princess Marries the Page" and "The Unseen", May 192? (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - [misc], 1919; undated; AUA pamphlet "The Layman and the Church" by Salem Hyde, member of MMC. Womens Alliance pamphlet "A Christmas Address" by Salem Hyde 1919. Remarks by Salem Hyde at funeral service of Charles De B. Mills, undated. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Why a Unitarian Believes and What" by H. W. Jordan, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Sketch of young boy by Ethel Blanchard Collver, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Order of service for ordination of Wilton Edson Cross, 3 sermons by Wilton Cross, printed pamphlet., 1918; undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Typed copy "The Poetic Beauty of the Bible" no author, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Printed sermon "When Half-Gods Go" Elizabeth Padgham, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Resolution passed by Women's Alliance: On death of Dr. Applebee (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Program of the Unitarian Club, MMC men's group, 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Order of service -- 100th anniversary of AUA, May 24, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Copies of information Gabriel Csiki from Unitarian church in Transylvania and announcement of his sermon on Sunday, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - History of Unitarianism. No author. Galpin?, undated; 30 pages partly typed and partly manuscript (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Press release, letter to congregation, program of conference of Mohawk Valley Unitarian churches held at MMC, April 1923 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - [misc], 1926; 1928; Announcement of pilgrimage to Barneveld church, June 1926. Publication of Meadville Theological School listing John Applebee as trustee 1928. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Seven programs of free organ recitals at MMC; dedication program, 1912; 1913,; 1914 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 2 orders of service for First Methodist Episcopal church, Syracuse, and announcing joint choirs with May Memorial., Dec. 1913; Apr. 1914 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - [Wilton E. Cross], 1919; undated; Pastor's 4-page report to Annual meeting by Rev. Wilton E. Cross 1919. Card announcing installation of WE Cross as minister of U. Society of Peterboro, NH. Order of Service of Installation of Rev. Cross at Peterboro. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Announcement of Lawn Festival to benefit Orphan's Home, June 1921 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Announcement of next four Sunday services (May) and announcement of joint Thanksgiving service and other future events (Nov), 1922 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Probate notices, 1919; 1923,; 1926-1927,; 1930,; undated; regarding money left to MMC by HL Snow 1930, WB Cogswell 1919, Cornelia S. Bigelow 1919, Anne H. Chase 1926, Mary E. Wieting Johnson 1927. Agnes A. Morgan, 1923. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Resolution from congregation to Wm. Howard Taft expressing gratitude for his efforts on behalf of international peace and good will, copy of accompanying letter., May, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Bound book listing names from membership book, 1838-1931 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Letters, service records, etc. relating to church members serving in WWI and WWII., Service records of MMChurch members 1917 -- already sent to Bird Library. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Flier and letter on joint program of Laymans League and Womens Alliance "Seeking the Cause of Industrial Harmony", Nov. 3, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Weekly Calendars with orders of Sunday services, 1911-1919 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Weekly calendars with orders of Sunday services, 1920-1926 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Weekly calendars with orders of Sunday services, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "The Bulletin" vol. 1, no. 2, May 5, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Waldemar W. Argow, Minister, 1930-1941
  - Order of service Kings Chapel, Boston MA. Rev. Argow, weekday ministry., March 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [50th Anniversary of MMC], Oct. 1935; Brief sketch of MMC, Syracuse, NY. In commemoration of the 50th Anniversary of MMC dedication, Oct 1885-1935, by Rev. Applebee. Copy of three hymns arranged by Mrs. Argow for the Anniversary service (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Orders of service: Argow installation; Valedictory, Oct 28, 1930; Feb. 23, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Report of evaluation committee, June 3, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - [Letters], 1930-1933; 1940-1941; Letter from Rev. Argow accepting call to May Memorial Church, June 1930. Invitation to installation service for Rev. Argow, Oct 28, 1930. Annual reports of the minister 1930, 1931, 1933. Letter from Argow to church members Dec. 29, 1940 re resignation. Letter to Editor (unsigned copy) Feb. 24, 1941 thanking the community for their good will and support. Invitation to reception Feb 16, 1941(?) for Dr. and Mrs. Argow at time of their leaving. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - [Letters], 1941; Copy of Board of Trustees resolution Jan 12, 1941 accepting Argow's resignation. Copy of letter to Henry Wilder Foote, Jan 7, 1941 inviting him to be interim minister at MMC. Copy of letter to HW Foote, Jan 14, 1941 stating terms of employment as interim. Letter from HW Foote Jan 16, 1941 accepting position as interim. Letter from FM. Eliot, June 19, 1941 supporting choice of Mr. Romig as new minister. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - [Letters], 1936-1940; Correspondence between WSYR and Rev. Argow concerning broadcasting Sunday services. 1937 to 1940. Letter from Onon Health Assn., Dec, 21, 1936 concerning radio broadcast and copy of Dr. Argow's presentation. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Copies of sermons and other writings by Rev. Argow, 1934-1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Published booklets, undated; An Argosy of Meditations, Victorious Living, Lenten meditations by Rev. Argow. 51 handwritten daily meditations for Lent and Easter. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Published book of meditations, titled "Beyond," Rev. Argow. Christmas poem, "A Thought for Christmas" from WWW Argow and Elsie Argow in Baltimore., 1929; 1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Centennial], 1938; Invitation to 1938 centennial. Card listing program for centennial week. List of people who sent congratulatory letters or wires. Letters received from Ellsworth Reamon, Wm. G. Vinal, Dana Greeley, John Haynes Holmes. Order of service for centennial service, Oct 16, 1938. Photograph of WWW, Elizabeth Padgham, Judge FH Hiscock who took part in the service. Program for centennial banquet, Oct 20, 1938. Names of people at the head table. Signatures of guests at the banquet. Photograph showing Frederick May Eliot, WWW Argow and William F. Canough. Press release to Herald Journal on centennial celebrations dated Oct. 12, 1938. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "A Backward Glance O'er Traveled Roads" by Helen Saddington and Elizabeth Walsh, 1838-1938; a history of MMC, two copies (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - [misc], 1935; undated; Photographs of interior of MMC, 1935 Easter decoration. Two small photos of interior, undated. Recollections by Joyce Ball made in 1988 re remodeling of sanctuary in Argow era. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - [Parish house], 1940-1941; Photo MMC exterior 1941? Article from AUA magazine Christian Register on acquisition of Parish house by MMC, undated, (1940?). Copy of original article sent to Christian Register Nov, 13, 1940, unsigned. Leather bound book listing contributions and workers in purchase and redecoration of Parish House, 1940-1941. Responsive reading and hymn used at dedication. (2 copies) Two copies of program for dedication of Parish House, Feb. 16, 1941. Press release for dedication of PH, undated, sent to Christian Register and Syracuse newspapers. Announcement of Congregational Meeting re purchase of parish house, Sept 27, 1940. Letter announcing dedication of PH dated Feb. 11, 1941, from Argow to church members. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Canvass brochure, Records of church activities., 1933-1939 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Papers by William Yerington, 2 typed, 1 printed (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mmemorial service of JL Cheney and funeral sermon by WWW Argow, Dec 2, 1932; March 16, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - [Hiscocks], 1935; 1937; Copy of condolence letter from MMC Board of Trustees to Judge Hiscock on Mrs. Hiscock's death April 1937. Sunset Vesper service in the Hiscock's garden June 7, 1935. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Excerpts from Board of Trustees meetings, Feb 8, 1890-Jan 1931 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Program for Mohawk Valley Conference held at MMC, Oct 24-25, 1930; 2 copies (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Information: annual Pilgrimage to Barneveld Church, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Argow's Statement of Arbitration Decision, Nov 1, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Appraisal committee, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Argow, miscellaneous writings (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Lists of Bd. Trustee Chairs (Presidents) and Organists (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Letter re Moravian Candlelight Service, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Orphan's Home Playground pamphlet by Mrs. James C. Tracy (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Annual reports, mostly handwritten, 1934 - 1941 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Data for Unitarian Year Book, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - [appraisals], Appraisals of James St. Church, 1927, 1932, 1936. Letter: Stained glass appraisal, marble busts of May and Calthrop, 1927. Women's Alliance inventory, 1932. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Argow letter, on spiritual revival in the congregation, May 9, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 3 letters regarding portraits of Samuel Joseph May (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Brief summary of church work, 1935, by Helen MacKnight and brief history of the Society prepared by Dr. Applebee. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Sermon by H. W. Foote, interim minister, Mar. 16, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Proposed budgets, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Laymen's League, 1928-1940; Programs. Minutes of executive committee. Annual Reports, some years missing. (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Orders of service, some volumes incomplete, from Vol. 1 through Vol. 11, 1930-1940; Feb. 1941 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Chart by A. W. Towne, "Facts Concerning Men's Clubs in Certain Syracuse Churches", 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Robert E. Romig, Minister, 1941-1946
  - [misc], 1943-1945; Flyer announcing church carnival, dated Apr 30, no year. notice that Temple Adath Yeshurun will award a certificate of merit to Mr. Romig on Feb 16, 1945. Notice of formation of church register Mar. 9, 1944. Copy of member questionnaire for register. Flyer, undated, asking for donations of clothing to USC for overseas. Annual Reports of Committees, 1943-44, 1944-45. Civic Lenten service program Apr 23, 1943. Four items from Symmachus Trading Company offering to sell MMC a letter signed by John Wilkinson in 1840. This letter is now in Storer file. Annual reports of committees 1941-42, 1942-43. Annual Report of RE Council. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - [Syracuse Boy's Club], 1942; Script of skit portraying Dr. Calthrop starting the Syracuse Boy's Club, undated. Order of service Dec. 13, 1942 when skit was presented. Two pamphlets of Syracuse Boy's Club undated. "Syracuse Boy's Club News, Nov 1942." Press release about the 50th Anniversary of the Syracuse Boy's Club. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brief biography and references for Mr. Romig, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Invitation card for reception for Rev. and Mrs. Romig on Sunday, Oct. 5. Order of service for installation of Rev. Romig on Oct 15, Oct 1941 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Two photographs of Mr. Romig (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - [resignation], 1946; Letter to church members from Mr. Romig announcing his resignation, dated Feb 26, 1946. Notice of special congregational meeting to act on Mr. Romig's resignation and to elect a pulpit committee dated Feb 26, 1946. Copy of letter of appreciation to Mr. Romig from the congregation, date added later, May 1946. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Eight sermons by Rev. Romig, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Meditation cards by Rev. Romig, 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Two letters regarding purchase of new chairs from Mottville Chair Works, Jan 1941 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Description of church property, 1940; 1942,; 1946; 472 James St., Oct. 1946; of parish house 466 James St. Nov. 1940; of parsonage 913 Comstock Ave. Jan 1942. Rough outline sketch of 466 James St. (Van Duyn property) Nov. 1940. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Letters to congregation, Feb. 14, 1945; from Bd of Trustees informing them of tribute to be paid to Rev. Romig at Friday services Feb. 16, 1945 at Temple Adath Yeshurun. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Outline history of May Memorial, one page (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Biographic sketch of Romig. Two items from UUA Archives, hand written notes on church improvement., 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - [stained glass windows], Chart showing location of stained glass windows in sanctuary 472 James St. Description of people to whom the windows were dedicated. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - [men and women in armed forces], 1943-1944; 1946; Order of Worship for service held at First Church, Boston, May 23, 1946 for those Unitarians who gave their lives in World War II. Covering letter from president of UUA. Romig letter Nov. 1944 to men and women in Armed Services. Dedication of Service Honor Roll May 16, 1943. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - MMC constitution in force in 1944 and proposed revision. Announcement of formation of revision committee. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Syracuse Consumer/Farmer Milk Cooperative about sale of milk to neighborhood families, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Elizabeth Padgham declining to serve on Board of Trustees, Sept 27, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence on broadcasts of Sunday sermons on station WSYR, July 1943 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Letter from W. W. Robbins of Meadville Theological School about Rev. Romig's lectures there, Mar. 7, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Orders of service, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Orders of service, 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters "Syracuse Unitarian", Sept. 1941-June 1945 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters "Syracuse Unitarian", Sept. 1945-June 1946 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Glenn O. Canfield, Minister, 1946-1952
  - [Letters], 1946; Letter from Canfield to Carl Ashley inquiring about his arrival and possible housing arrangements, June 13, 1946. Copy of letter to Canfield regarding sharing parsonage with Romigs, unsigned, July 1, 1946. Letter: Canfield to Carl Ashley, will arrive July 31, dated July 4, 1946. Copy of letter Ashley to Canfield: repair and redecoration of parsonage, July 10, 1946. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Installation of Rev. Canfield, Order of service,, Oct. 13, 1946. Invitation card for installation. 3 copies of letters to people invited to installation: date changed to Oct. 18, 1946. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 2 photographs and a negative of Rev. Canfield, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Radio sermons by Rev. Canfield, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 2 pamphlets by Canfield, May 1946; undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Architect's conception of the facade of church of the Messiah (State and Burnet Sts.) with letter from artist Thomas J. McCormick, Jr., July 30, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Religion and the Tax-Supported School" by Eleanor Rosebrugh, AUA, 1949; 40-page paper (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Article from Christian Register, "Inside UUA: II - The Syracuse Method", Jan. 1949; Photograph of church members at kick-off dinner for United Unitarian Appeal, used in above article. Smaller copy of same photo dated Oct. 28, 1948 and naming speaker, John Fisher. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 2 photos of group at grave of Samuel J. May, May, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - [Boy Scouts], Letter from Richard Greene to MMUS Board President: the Layman's League requests use of a room for a Boy Scout Troop they will sponsor. Copies of letters from Carl Ashley to: 1) Scout-master about damage done by boys to building and furnishings, Dec. 6, 1947. 2) local BSA Executive re discontinuing use of church for scout meetings, Jan 27, 1949. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence relating to roof repairs, June 13, 1946 to Aug 23, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Half-page print of 472 James St. and Parish house (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Leather bound book of signatures, people attending 50th anniversary celebration of ordination of Rev. Elizabeth Padgham (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - [Padgham house], Stereoscope slide of Padgham home, 17 Shonnard St., (or #120?) Syracuse. List of beneficiaries in Padgham's will, dated Dec. 15, 1952. 5 x 7 portrait of E. Padgham April, 1933. Clergyman's Record: funeral of E. Padgham, Dec. 4, 1952, by Robert Zoerheide. Judicial settlement of Padgham's will dated Apr.16, 1954. Letter from executor to MMC re enclosed check distributive share of Padgham estate. Judicial settlement of accounts Padgham estate filed April 15, 1954. Letter from First Trust to Brainard Fancher re insurance policies on Padgham home. Record of money received by MMUS from sale of Padgham furnishings, dated Feb. 19, 1953. List of investment holdings in Padgham estate, copy of letter from HB Fancher re disposal of some estate holdings, Jan 27, 1954. Copy of preliminary report of Committee on Padgham estate, undated. Copy of last will and testament of E. Padgham. Photo of Padgham house, 120 Shonnard St, Syracuse (or # 17?). (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 8 x 10 photo of Rev. Elizabeth Padgham at dinner with Gladys Timmerman (server), Rev. Dale Dewitt, Rev. Canfield., Sept 25, 1951; also matted copy of 8 x 10 photo above, 8 x 10 photo of all guests at the table. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Copy of letter from Canfield inviting Rev. Keubler to dinner honoring E. Manwell and J. Gould. Photo taken at dinner: E. Manwell, F. M. Eliot, Warren Walsh, J. Gould., Sep 1949 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 5-page lecture: "How Can We Improve Our Schools?" by Dr. W. D. Sheldon, Sunday forum, May 7, 1950; The Forum was a regular activity every Sunday before the service (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Sermon by William Yerington given at MMC, Layman's Sunday, May 23, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Church mailing list (copy), March, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - [misc financial], 1946-1947; Budget passed at annual Meeting, June 6, 1946. Canvass letter from Finance committee Chair J. C. Timmerman, May 13, 1947. Canvass letter from President C. Ashley May 8, 1947. Five letters (4 copies, 1 original) re mortgage to UUA for loan to repair roof. Dates: Oct. 1946 - Feb 1947. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Committee reports for annual Meeting and final budget, Jun 12 1947 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - [Letters], Letter to members from Glenn and Betty Canfield Nov. 11, 1951 requesting permission to continue living at parsonage until end of January, 1952. Letter to congregation dated Dec 6, 1951 inviting them to attend reception honoring Canfields on Dec. 16, 1951. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - [Pulpit Committee], 1951-1952; Ballot form for Pulpit Committee election on Nov 18, 1951. Seven pages of needs and suggestions: "What Do We Need from the Church" resulting from neighborhood meetings held Jan 13 - 21, 1952? Three-page summary of findings of neighborhood meetings. Report of neighborhood meetings held Feb 10-25, 1952: "To Meet Our Needs" -- suggestions for action. Summary of replies to Pulpit Committee Questionnaire. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - [misc], 1950-1951; Announcement to congregation of intention to enlarge parish house, Dec. 15, 1950. Dedication ceremony for new kindergarten room Nov 2, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Reports of president and committee chairs, annual meeting, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - [misc], 1950; Charter and bylaws of MMC branch of Unitarian Service Committee. Announcements of meeting to be held Oct. 10, 1950 about USC activities. First Annual Report to members of MMC branch of USC giving history and finances of the committee from MS Dooley, president of USC branch. Photo undated: Rev. Romig, Eleanor Rosebrugh, Rev. Canfield, Elizabeth and Warren Walsh. Letter from MMC/USC committee to members concerning changes in its charter and by-laws. May 29. 1950. Copy of proposed changes to charter and by-laws, page 1 missing. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Letter announcing opening of Beacon Bookshop at MMC. Two fliers about Fairless Fair, dated., Jan 22, 1951; Oct. 19, 1951;; Nov 15, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Review of church activities in 1946-1947 church year by finance committee,., May 13, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Syracuse Public Library Director acknowledging gift of books (not listed) from MMUS, Nov. 10, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Steering committee members and Social Action Committee program, Nov. 3, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Orders of service, Sept 1946-June 1949 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Orders of service, Sept 1949-March 16, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Newsletters, 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Syracuse Unitarian Aug 1946-Dec. 1947. May Memorial Times May-June 1947 (news and annual reports). Unitarian Newsletter Jan. 1948-June 1949.
- John Fuller, Minister, 1961-1973
  - Reports of pulpit committee concerning the appointment of Rev. Fuller as minister, 1961; vacant pulpit notice; brief introduction to church and community; summary of replies to questionnaire; correspondence with Fuller (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pulpit committee report to Board of Trustees, 1961; special committee to study the roles and responsibilities of ministry; special committee report to pulpit committee (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Board of Trustees inviting members and friends to the installation service for Rev. Fuller, 1962; correspondence; copy of installation service program (Box 6, Folder 3)